Guide to the Trent Collection of Whitmaniana, 1841-1992, bulk 1845-1849, 1854-1857, and 1864-1892
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Writings Series, 1841-1944 and undated
  - Proofs Subseries, 1874-1891 and undated
    - Halcyon Days, undated, Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 5 (Box III-8B, Pr. 5)
      Proof copy with corrections, presumably by Whitman
    - Have We a National Literature?, North American Review, 1891 Mar. (P), Former call number: III-8C, Pr. 6 (Box III-8C, Pr. 6)
    - A Memorandum at a Venture, North American Review, 1882 June (A), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 7 (Box III-8B, Pr. 7)
    - November Boughs, undated Page proofs, pp. 5-45, preceded by a 4-page review clipped from the Chicago Daily News, 9 Feb. 1889., Former call number: I-1 (Box I-1)
    - November Boughs, undated Page proofs, pp. 46-92, Former call number: I-1 (Box I-1)
    - November Boughs, undated Page proofs, pp. 93-140, Former call number: I-1 (Box I-1)
    - Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, Harper's, 1885 Jan. (P), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 9 (Box III-8B, Pr. 9)
      Cf. Books and Periodicals Containing Contributions by Whitman Subseries.
    - Old Age's Lambent Peaks, undated, Former call number: III-8C, Pr. 10 (Box III-8C, Pr. 10)
    - Patroling Barnegat, 1880 June 3 (A), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 11 (Box III-8B, Pr. 11)
    - Preface, undated, Former call number: III-8C, Pr. 12 (Box III-8C, Pr. 12)
      Preface to Three Tales, by W. D. O'Connor
    - Shakespeare for America, The Poet Lore, 1890 Sept. 15 (P), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 13 (Box III-8B, Pr. 13)
    - Summer Days in Canada, London Advertiser, 1890 June 22 (P), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 14A (Box III-8B, Pr. 14A)
    - Sunday with the Insane, London Advertiser, 1890 June 22 (P), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 14B (Box III-8B, Pr. 14B)
    - Thanks in Old Age, undated, Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 15 (Box III-8B, Pr. 15)
    - To Get the Final Lilt of Songs, undated, Former call number: III-8C, Pr. 10 (Box III-8C, Pr. 10)
    - To the Sun-Set Breeze, undated, Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 16 (Box III-8B, Pr. 16)
      Cf. Correspondence From or By Whitman Subseries. A second copy of this proof is included in a letter from Whitman to J. D. Stoddart.
    - A Twilight Song, The Century, 1890 May (P), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 17 (Box III-8B, Pr. 17)
    - Walt Whitman: The True Reminiscence of his Writings, The West Jersey Press, 1876 May 24 (P), Former call number: III-8C, Pr. 18 (Box III-8C, Pr. 18)
    - Walt Whitman's Actual American Position, The West Jersey Press, 1876 Jan. 26 (P) (2 copies), Former call number: III-8C, Pr. 19 (Box III-8C, Pr. 19)
    - With Husky-Haughty Lips, O Sea!, Harper's, 1883 Nov. (A), Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 20 (Box III-8B, Pr. 20)
    - Your kind invitation to visit you and deliver a poem for the 33d Anniversary of founding Santa Fe..., undated, Former call number: III-8B, Pr. 21 (Box III-8B, Pr. 21)
  - Poems Set to Music Subseries, 1901-1933
    Published versions of certain of Whitman's poems that were set to music by different composers. Dates of copyright, rather than those of composition, are given below. Several of the titles in the Trent Collection are described in greater detail in Bella C. Landauer, Leaves of Music by Walt Whitman, call number Trent I-9A. Entries for those titles listed in Leaves of Music include Landauer's catalogue number. Listed alphabetically by composer.
    - Bacon, Ernst: Eight Songs from Whitman, Letter press by Grabhorn, San Francisco, 1930 (Box I-9B)
    - Bridge, Frank: The Last Invocation, Winthrop Rogers, Ltd., London, 1919 (Landauer 19) (Box I-9B)
    - Campbell-Tipton, Louis: Op. 32, No. 1, Rhapsodie, G. Schirmer, New York, 1919 (Landauer 23) (Box I-9B)
    - Campbell-Tipton, Louis: Two Songs to Words by Walt Whitman: I. 'Elegy,' II. 'At the Tomb, The Boston Music Company, Boston, 1918 (Landauer 27)
    - Dalmas, Philip: As I watch'd the Ploughman Ploughing, and Other Chants of Freedom,, Novello and Company, London, 1901 (Landauer 39) (Box I-9B)
    - Dalmas, Philip: As I watch'd..., including woodcuts by Wharton Esherick, London, 1901 (Landauer 40)
    - Gaul, Harvey B.: I Hear America Singing, C. C. Birchard and Co., Boston 1925 (Landauer 58) (Box I-9A)
    - Kernochan, Marshall: Out of the Rolling Ocean..., C. W. Thompson and Co., Boston, 1908 (Landauer 89) (Box I-9B)
    - Kernochan, Marshall: Out of the Rolling Ocean..., Galaxy Music Corporation, New York, 1933
    - Kernochan, Marshall: Two Songs: I. 'Song of Ylen,' [words by Richard Hovey], II. 'We Two Together,' [words by Whitman], G. Schirmer, New York, 1911
    - Kernochan, Marshall: We Two Together, Galaxy Music Corporation, New York, 1933
    - Phippen, Joshua: O Captain My Captain, Essex Institute, Salem [Mass.], 1909 (Box I-9A)
    - Powers, Ada Weigel: The Last Invocation, Edward Schuberth and Co., New York, 1927 (Landauer 105a) (Box I-9B)
    - Scott, Cyril: My Captain, Elkin and Co., Ltd., London, 1904 (Box I-9B)
    - Spalding, Eva Ruth: Trois Melodies pour Chant et Piano, Editions Maurice Senart, Paris, 1923 (Landauer 120) (Box I-9B)
    - Storey-Smith, Warren: The Last Invocation, Bruce Humphries, Inc., Boston, 1934 (Box I-9B)
    - Tomlins, W. L, editor: The Laurel Song-Book for Advanced Classes in Schools, Academies, Choral Societies, etc., C. C. Birchard and Company, Boston, 1901 (Box I-9A)
    - Williams, R. Vaughan: Three Poems by Walt Whitman, Oxford University Press, London, 1925 (Box I-9B)
    - Whithorne, Emerson: Invocation, Composers' Music Corp., New York, 1921 (Landauer 136) (Box I-9B)
  - Periodicals and Books Containing Contributions by Whitman Subseries, 1841-1924
    Periodicals and books containing poems, essays, and letters by Whitman. Includes the first and only issue of the abolitionist newspaper Brooklyn Freeman, which Whitman edited. The copy in the Trent Collection is the only one known to be extant. Divided into two sections, the first of which lists periodicals in the Trent Collection to which Whitman contributed, and the second of which lists books. Listed alphabetically by periodical or book title.
    - Periodicals
      - Atlantic Monthly
        - No. 30: Bardic Symbols, pp. 445-7, 1860 Apr., Former call number: Box W1
        - No. 558: An American Printer, pp. 460-70, 1904 Apr., Former call number: W615A
      - Bitzaron
        - Crossing Brooklyn Ferry, (in Hebrew) p. 163, 1949 June/July, Former call number: Box W1
      - Brooklyn Freeman
        - Vol. I, no. 1, edited by Walt Whitman. Only extant copy known. 1848 Sept. 9, Former call number: III-6B (Box III-6B)
      - Brother Jonathan
        - Vol. I, no. 9: Boz and Democracy, pp. 243-4, 1842 Feb. 26, Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
      - The Century Illustrated Monthly Magazine
        - Vol. XXXIX, no. 4: Old Age's Ship and Crafty Death, p. 553, 1890 Feb., Former call number: Box W1
      - The Democratic Review
        - Vol. XL, No. LI: The Angel of Tears, p. 282, 1842 Sept., Former call number: Box W1
      - Ellery Queen's Mystery Magazine
        - One Wicked Impulse! p. 92, 1954 Jan., Former call number: Box W1
      - The Galaxy
        - Vol. IV, no. 5: A Card of Harvest for 1867, pp. 605-9, 1867 Sept., Former call number: IX G146 A
        - Vol. XI: O Star of France!, p. 817, 1871 Jan.-July
      - Harper's New Monthly Magazine
        - Vol. LXX, no. 416: Of That Blithe Throat of Thine, p. 64, 1885 Jan., Former call number: Box W1
          Cf. Proofs Subseries.
        - "Wood Odors," p. 43, 1960 Dec., Former call number: Box W1
      - Ha-Galgal
        - Vol. I, No. 17: Ship of State (in Hebrew), 1944 Mar. 2, Former call number: Box W1
      - Inoue English Correspondence School
        - English correspondence course, 1955 July, Former call number: Box W1
      - Israel Argosy
        - No. 7: p. 120, 1960, Former call number: Box W1
      - Life Illustrated
        - Vol. I, no. 13: Christmas at Grace, p. 97, 1856 Jan. 26, Former call number: I-7 (Box I-7)
        - Vol. I, no. 24: America's Mightiest Inheritance, pp. 185-6, 1856 Apr. 2
        - Vol. II, no. 2: Voltaire, p. 9, 1856 May 10
        - Vol. II, no. 3: Fanny Fern's Opinion of Walt Whitman, pp. 20-1, 1856 May 17
        - Vol. II, no. 11: New York Dissected, part 1, p. 85, 1856 July 12
        - Vol. II, no. 12: New York Dissected, part 2, p. 93, 1856 July 19
        - Vol. II, no. 14: New York Dissected, part 3, pp. 108-9, 1856 Aug. 2
        - Vol. II, no. 15: New York Dissected, part 4, p. 116, 1856 Aug. 9
        - Vol. II, no. 16: New York Dissected, part 5, p. 125, 1856 Aug. 16
        - Vol. II, no. 17: New York Dissected, part 6, p. 133, 1856 Aug. 23
        - Vol. II, no. 22: Advertisement for second edition of Leaves of Grass, 1856 Sept. 27
      - Lippincott's Monthly Magazine
        - Vol. XXXIX, no. 229: My Book and I, pp. 121-7, 1887 Jan., Former call number: Box W1
        - pp. 376-388, 1891 Mar., Former call number: Box W2
      - The Literary Review
        - Vol. 4, No. 1: Criticism, p. 49, 1960 Autumn, Former call number: Box W2
      - The Magazine of Poetry
        - Vol. I: Selected Poems, pp. 15-23, 1889, Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
      - Le Navire d'Argent
        - Vol. 2, No. 10, 1926 Mar., Former call number: Box W2
      - The New World
        - Extra Series, no. 34: Franklin Evans; or, the Inebriate. A Tale of the Times, pp. 1-31, 1842 Nov., Former call number: I-7 (Box I-7)
      - The North American Review
        - The Poetry of the Future, 1881 Feb., Former call number: Box W2
      - The Northern Pioneer
        - Vol. I, no. 15: Wild Frank's Return, p. 116, 1848 Oct. 7, Former call number: III-6B (Box III-6B)
      - La Nouvelle Critique
        - Fragments politiques inedits, pp. 239-256, 1955 July-Aug., Former call number: Box W2
      - The Portland (Me.) Transcript
        - Vol. XIV, no. 19: Resurgemus, p. 148, 1850 Aug. 24, Former call number: III-6B (Box III-6B)
        - Vol. XXIII, no. 43: You and Me and Today, p. 342, 1860 Jan. 28, Former call number: III-6B (Box III-6B)
      - The Rising Generation
        - Walt Whitman Special Number 150 (in Japanese), 1969 June, Former call number: Box W2
      - Sozialistische Monatshefte
        - An dich. Ubertragen von Max Hayek, p. 141, 1918, Former call number: Box W2
      - Transactions of the Buffalo Historical Society
        - Vol. III: Red Jacket, (From Aloft), p. 105, 1885, Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
      - Trends and Tides
        - Vol. 4, No. 4: The Eighteenth Presidency, p. 1, 1948 Oct.-Dec., (2 copies); Former call number: Box W2
      - The United States Magazine and Democratic Review
        - NS Vol. IX, no. 38: Death in the School-Room. A Fact, pp. 177-81, 1841 Aug., Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
        - NS Vol. IX, no. 41: Wild Frank's Return, pp. 476-82, 1841 Nov.
        - NS Vol. IX, no. 42: Bervance: or, Father and Son, pp. 560-8, 1841 Dec.
        - NS Vol. X, no. 43: The Tomb-Blossoms, pp. 62-8, 1842 Jan.
        - NS Vol. X, no. 47: The Child-Ghost; A Story of the Last Loyalist, pp. 451-9, 1842 May
        - Vol. XVII, no. 89: A Dialogue, pp. 360-4, 1845 Nov.
      - Walt Whitman in the Ukraine, trans. by Korotich, 1965, Former call number: Box W2
    - Books
      - Essays from The Critic, by John Burroughs, et al., 1882, Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
        By Whitman: Death of Carlyle, pp. 31-7; Death of Longfellow, pp. 41-5
      - Et Cetera: A Collector's Scrap-Book, edited by Vincent Startett, no. 144 of 625 copies, 1924, Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
        By Whitman: Fragments, p. 193; Broadway 1861, p. 195
      - In Re Walt Whitman, edited by Horace L. Traubel, et al., 1893, (2 copies); Former call number: Trent IV
      - The Letters of Anne Gilchrist and Walt Whitman, edited by Thomas B. Harned, 1918, Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
      - The Poets' Tribute to Garfield: A Collection of Many Memorial Poems, 1882
        By Whitman: The Sobbing of the Bells, p. 71
      - Voices from the Press: A Collection of Sketches, Essays, and Poems by Practical Printers, edited by James J. Brenton, 1850, Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
        By Whitman: The Tomb-Blossoms, pp. 27-33
  - Editions of Whitman's Writings Subseries, 1855-1944
    Published versions of Whitman's poetry and prose. Entries below are listed alphabetically by title and chronologically within title headings. With the exception of Sotsukwa's Japanese translation of Leaves of Grass, which is cataloged under Leaves of Grass, all translations are listed alphabetically by title as it is spelled in the language of translation. Editions of Leaves of Grass listed chronologically.
    - After All, Not to Create Only. Boston: Roberts Brothers, 1871., (2 copies); Former call number: II-1 (Box II-1)
    - An American Primer. Edited by Horace Traubel. Boston: Small, Maynard and Company, 1904., Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - Autobiographia, or The Story of a Life. Prose selections. New York: Charles L. Webster and Co.; London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1892., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Autobiographia, or The Story of a Life. Edited by Arthur Stedman. Fiction, Fact and Fancy Series. New York: Charles L. Webster and Co., 1892., Former call number: II-2, shelved as 1892a (Box II-2, shelved as 1892a)
    - Calamus. Edited by Richard Maurice Bucke. Letters from Whitman to Peter Doyle, 1868-1880. Boston: Laurens Maynard, 1897., (2 copies); Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
      Cf. From or By Whitman Subseries.
    - Calamus. Edited and translated by Leon Bazalgette (French trans.). Geneva: Editions du Sablier, 1919., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - A Child's Reminiscence. Edited by Thomas O. Mabbott and Rollo G. Silver. Seattle: University of Washington Book Store, 1930., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Christmas cards from Rollo G. Silver to Louise Hall, featuring poems by Whitman, 1928-1986, (3 folders); Former call number: Box M1
    - Complete Poems and Prose of Walt Whitman, 1855-1888. Autograph copy. [No publisher identified in Frey], Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
    - Complete Prose Works. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1892., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - The Complete Writings of Walt Whitman, "Camden Edition." Edited by Richard Maurice Bucke, Thomas B. Harned, and Horace L. Traubel; additional material contributed by Oscar Lovell Triggs. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1902. (10 vols.), Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - Criticism, An Essay. Newark, N.J.: The Carteret Book Club, 1913., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Democratic Vistas, and Other Papers. London: Walter Scott; Toronto: W. J. Gage and Co., 1888., Former call number: II-1 (Box II-1)
    - Digte. Edited and translated by Johannes V. Jensen and Otto Gelsted (Danish trans.). Kobenhavn; Kristiania: Nordisk Forlag, 1919., Former call number: I-4 (Box I-4)
    - Drum Taps. New York: Grosset and Dunlap, 1936., Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
    - Feuilles d'herbe. Edited and translated by Leon Bazalgette (French trans.). Paris: Mercure de France, 1909. (2 vols), Former call number: I-4 (Box I-4)
    - Feuilles d'herbe. Paris: Mercure de France, 1922. (2 vols.)
    - Finf un zwanzig Lieder. Edited and translated by Dr. A. Eisen, in Hebrew characters. New York: Farlag Idish Leben, 1934.
    - The Gathering of the Forces: Editorial, Essays, Literary and Dramatic Reviews, And Other Material written by Walt Whitman as Editor of The Brooklyn Daily Eagle in 1846 and 1847. Edited by Cleveland Rogers and John Black. New York and London: G. P. Putnam's Sons, 1920. (2 vols.), Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Gems from Walt Whitman. Edited by Elizabeth Porter Gould. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1889., Former call number: II-1 (Box II-1)
    - Good-Bye My Fancy. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1891., (2 copies); Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - Grashalme. Edited and translated into German by Karl Knortz and T. W. Rolleston. Zurich: Verlags-Magazin (J. Schabelitz), 1889.
    - Grashalme. With illustrations by Willi Jaeckel. Berlin: Erich Reiss Verlag, 1920., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - The Half-Breed and Other Stories. Edited by Thomas Olive Mabbott, with woodcuts by Allen Lewis. New York: Columbia University Press, 1927., Former call number: III-4 (Box III-4)
    - I Sit and Look Out. Edited by Emory Holloway and Vernolian Schwartz. New York: Columbia University Press, 1932., Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - Lafayette in Brooklyn. Introduction by John Burroughs. New York: George D. Smith, 1905., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Leaves of Grass, first edition, first issue (2 copies). Brooklyn: [Walt Whitman], 1855., Former call number: I-5B (Box I-5B)
    - Leaves of Grass, first edition, second issue (1 copy); first edition, English export (1 copy). Brooklyn: [Walt Whitman], 1855., Former call number: I-5C (Box I-5C)
    - Leaves of Grass, second edition. Brooklyn: [Walt Whitman], 1856., Former call number: I-2 (Box I-2)
    - Leaves of Grass, third edition. Boston: Thayer and Eldridge, 1860-1861., Former call number: I-2 or I-5A (Box I-2 or I-5A)
    - Leaves of Grass, Worthington's pirated edition. Boston: Thayer and Eldridge, 1860-1861., (2 copies)
    - Leaves of Grass, fourth edition. Presentation copy, inscribed by Whitman. New York, 1867.
    - Leaves of Grass, Electrotyped by Smith and McDougal, New York; published in Washington, D.C., 1871
    - Leaves of Grass, with Passage to India. Washington, D.C.: [No publisher identified in Frey], 1871.
    - Leaves of Grass, fifth edition. Washington, D.C.: [No publisher identified in Frey], 1872.
    - Leaves of Grass, As a Strong Bird on Pinions Free, and Other Poems. Washington, D.C.: [No publisher identified in Frey], 1872., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Leaves of Grass, sixth edition. Camden, N.J., 1876., Former call number: I-2 (Box I-2)
    - Leaves of Grass, sixth edition. Presentation copy, inscribed by Whitman. Camden, N.J., 1876.
    - Leaves of Grass, seventh edition, third Boston edition. Boston: James R. Osgood and Company, 1881-1882., (2 copies)
    - Leaves of Grass, seventh edition (reprint). Rees, Welsh and Co., 1882., Former call number: I-3 (Box I-3)
    - Leaves of Grass. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1884.
    - Leaves of Grass, seventh edition (reprint). Glasgow: Wilson and McCormick, 1884.
    - Leaves of Grass, with Sands at Seventy and A Backward Glance o'er Travel'd Roads, eighth edition. [No publisher identified in Frey], 1889.
    - Leaves of Grass, including Sands at Seventy...1st Annex, Good-Bye my Fancy...2d Annex, A Backward Glance o'er Traveled Roads, and Portrait from Life, ninth edition, second issue. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1891-1892.
    - Leaves of Grass. Boston: Small, Maynard and Cos., 1898.
    - Leaves of Grass. Philadelphia: David McKay, ca. 1900.
    - Leaves of Grass. New York: M. Kennerling, 1914.
    - Leaves of Grass, facsimile of 1855 first edition. Portland, Me.: Thomas Bird Mosher and William Francis Gable, 1919., Former call number: I-5 (Box I-5)
    - Leaves of Grass. Edited and translated by Tomita Sotsukwa (Japanese translation). Tokyo and Osaka: [No publisher identified in Frey], 1919-1920. (2 vols), Former call number: I-4 (Box I-4)
    - Leaves of Grass. "Inclusive Edition." Edited by Emory Holloway. Garden City, N.Y.: Doubleday, Page and Company, 1927., Former call number: I-3 (Box I-3)
    - Leaves of Grass. Introduction by Carolyn Wells. New York: Limited Editions Club, 1929., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Leaves of Grass. New York: Random House, 1930., Former call number: I-6A (Box I-6A)
    - Leaves of Grass. New York: Aventine, 1931., Former call number: I-3 (Box I-3)
    - Leaves of Grass, facsimile of 1855 first edition. Introduction by Clifton Joseph Furness. New York: Columbia University Press for the Facsimile Text Society, 1939., Former call number: I-5B or III-11 (Box I-5B or III-11)
    - Leaves of Grass. New York: Modern Library, 1940., Former call number: I-3 (Box I-3)
    - Leaves of Grass. Edited by Christopher Morley, with illustrations by Lewis C. Daniel. New York: Doubleday, Doran and Co., Inc., 1940., Former call number: I-6 or III-11 (Box I-6 or III-11)
    - Leaves of Grass. Introduction by Mark Van Doren, photographs by Edward Weston. New York: Limited Editions Club, 1942., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Leaves of Grass. Illustrations by Boyd Hanna. Mount Vernon, NY: Peter Pauper Press, 1950., Former call number: I-6B (Box I-6B)
    - Leaves of Grass by Walt Whitman: Preface to the Original Edition, 1855. Trubner and Co., 1881., (3 copies); Former call number: I-6C (Box I-6C)
    - Leaves of Grass Imprints: American and European Criticisms on Leaves of Grass. Boston: Thayer and Eldridge, 1860., Former call number: I-2 (Box I-2)
    - Letters Written by Walt Whitman To His Mother, 1866-1872. Introduction by Rollo G. Silver. New York: Alfred F. Goldsmith, 1936., Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
    - Memoranda, with Democratic Vistas. Washington, D.C.: [No publisher identified in Frey], 1871., Former call number: II-1 (Box II-1)
    - Memoranda During the War. Camden, N.J.: [Walt Whitman], 1875-1876., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Memories of President Lincoln. Portland, Me.: Thomas B. Mosher, 1912., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - Memories of President Lincoln and Other Lyrics of the War. Portland, Me.: Thomas B. Mosher, 1906., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Natuurleven, first Dutch edition. Edited and translated into Dutch by Maurits Wagenvoort. Haarlem: Erven F. Bohn, 1898., Former call number: I-4 (Box I-4)
    - New York Dissected. Edited by and introduction by Emory Holloway and Ralph Adimari. New York: Rufus Rockwell Wilson, Inc., 1936., Former call number: II-11 (Box II-11)
    - Notes and Fragments. Edited by Richard Maurice Bucke. London, Ontario: A. Talbot and Co., 1899., Former call number: III-11 (Box III-11)
    - A Note about Whitman's Essay on Poe, by Rollo G. Silver. Reprinted from American Literature, vol. VII, no. 1, 1935 Mar., Former call number: Trent V Pam Case
    - November Boughs. Philadelphia: David McKay, 1888., (2 copies); Former call number: II-4 (Box II-4)
    - O Captain! San Francisco: Privately printed, 1935., Former call number: I-7 (Box I-7)
    - Ode de la France. Translated by Leon Bazalgette. Paris: La Belle Edition, undated.
    - One Precious Leaf from the 1st Edition. New York: Bennett Book Studios, 1930., Former call number: I-6A (Box I-6A)
    - Out of the Cradle Endlessly Rocking. New York: The June House, 1926., Former call number: II-3 (Box II-3)
    - Pictures. Edited by and introduction by Emory Holloway. New York: The June House, 1927; London: Faber and Gwyer, 1927.
    - Poems by Walt Whitman. Edited by William Michael Rossetti. London: John Camden Hotten, 1868., Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Poems by Walt Whitman. The Masterpiece Library Series, no. XXVII. London: "Review of Reviews" Office, 1895., Former call number: Pam 12mo #11, c.1
    - Sea Drift. New York: Hearst's International Library Company, 1919[?], Former call number: II-2 (Box II-2)
    - Selected Poems. Edited by Arthur Stedman. Fact, Fiction, and Fancy Series. New York: Charles L. Webster and Co., 1892.
    - Selections from the Prose and Poetry of Walt Whitman. Edited and introduced by Oscar Lovell Triggs. Boston: Small, Maynard and Co., 1898.
    - Seven Letters of Walt Whitman, by Rollo G. Silver. Reprinted from American Literature, vol. VII, no. 1, 1935 Mar., Former call number: Trent V Pam Case
    - Salut au Monde! Illustrations by Vojtech Pressig. New York: Random House, 1930., Former call number: I-7 (Box I-7)